<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DFIR ≫ Blog by whois</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/</link><description>Recent content on DFIR ≫ Blog by whois</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>It's all about forensics</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 14:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.dfir.fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[0x08] Log4shell memos</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/12/0x08-log4shell-memos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/12/0x08-log4shell-memos/</guid><description>Image source: Kevin Beaumont, Twitter
On Friday 10th of December 2021, internet was set on fire. Or technically internet was full of flammable material and someone shared matches to everyone on that day. In this blog post, I will present my thoughts about the case.
TL;DR Do not flame the developers of Log4j or open-source stuff in general for this issue Always use the newest version of Log4j If patching or mitigating is not possible in short term, organizations should consider taking down the vulnerable service until it has been fixed Use default deny outbound Assume breach Happy hunting!</description></item><item><title>[0x07] Migration to Github</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/09/0x07-migration-to-github/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 16:04:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/09/0x07-migration-to-github/</guid><description>I’ve decided to change my blog from self-hosted jekyll site to auto deployed Github hugo page.
Because of this, my blog’s RSS feed will also change. You can find the new RSS link from footer.
I will likely release more but less structured content on this blog in the future.
blog.dfir.fi CNAME will soon point to https://who1s.github.io</description></item><item><title>[0x06] Cyber Security Essentials CTF</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x06-cyber-security-essentials-ctf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x06-cyber-security-essentials-ctf/</guid><description>Cyber Security Essentials is a course series I was organizing in HelSec with Future Female. CSE had 6 lectures and the CTF was organized at the end of the course. The course was aimed for female who are interested working in technical side of the Cyber Security OR just started in the field. This CTF was made 99% by me alone and was purposed to be entry level. More information about the course series can be found from here.</description></item><item><title>[0x05] Phishing MFA accounts</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x05-phishing-mfa-accounts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x05-phishing-mfa-accounts/</guid><description>MFA is usually considered secure. It however can be bypassed by phishing. I made this phishing demo using drk1wi&amp;rsquo;s tool Modlishka. The tool default templates are little bit outdated so here&amp;rsquo;s also instructions how to make it work against G-Suite accounts. This is not a new thing, I just wanted to check if it still works. =)
The full configuration is on Github.
Demo Put it to the container I decided to do quick and dirty dockerization for the tool:</description></item><item><title>[0x04] Installing RegRipper on Linux</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/02/0x04-installing-regripper-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/02/0x04-installing-regripper-on-linux/</guid><description>RegRipper is a tool made by H. Carvey (keydet89) for Windows registry analysis. The tool is perl script that is made to run on Windows. The tool can be installed on Linux distros but I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet found good instructions how to do it to share so I decided to make my own. I use the tool on the forensic courses I teach. Kudos to keydet89 for making this awesome tool.</description></item><item><title>[0x03] Disobey 2020 puzzle writeup</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</guid><description>Disobey is a Finnish hacker/cyber security conference. They release every year a hacker challenge and 50 first who solve it, get to buy the special &amp;ldquo;hacker ticket&amp;rdquo; with a cheaper price than a regular ticket. The badge that comes with the ticket is also visually different looking than a normal ticket. At the first I have to admit, this year the challenge was harder than in previous years. This was my third time I tried to do the challenge and the third time I managed to solve it.</description></item><item><title>[0x02] Late wedding gift</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/07/0x02-late-wedding-gift/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/07/0x02-late-wedding-gift/</guid><description>This is kinda old story but I wanted to share it with you as I find it somewhat funny. Sadly now, when I finally had spare time to spend with the document, the host it tries to connect is down. Hopefully you still enjoy the read!
Me and my wife got married 1,5 years ago in Las Vegas. As usual, I had to confirm the reservation by sending an email to the chapel.</description></item><item><title>[0x01] SANS 2019 &amp; BSides Orlando</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x01-sans-2019-bsides-orlando/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x01-sans-2019-bsides-orlando/</guid><description>Few weeks ago I left cold Finland and headed to Orlando to attend SANS FOR610 (Reverse-Engineering Malware). After signing up and buying flight tickets, I noticed that BSides Orlando was held just few days before the course started. I though &amp;ldquo;What the hell&amp;rdquo; and bought a ticket to that event as well. BSides is Disobey (Finnish hacking/cyber security event) like event and has talks, workshops, CTF, soldering station etc&amp;hellip;
BSides was held at Full Sail University near Orlando.</description></item><item><title>[0x00] Hello World!</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x00-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x00-hello-world/</guid><description>I decided to start blogging because
I suck at remembering stuff -&amp;gt; If I write it publicly down, I will most likely remember it There&amp;rsquo;s no DFIR blogs in Finland (at least I don&amp;rsquo;t know of them) There&amp;rsquo;s never too many projects, right? My bio can be found on about-page</description></item><item><title>/whois whois</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/about/</guid><description>Ehlo, my name is Juho and people tend to know me as whois online (or mr. salt guy). I am 31-year-old techie guy who likes digital forensics and incident response (DFIR).
I am currently GREM, OSCP, CISSP, GCFA and GMON certified and work as a InfoSec Specialist for NCSC-FI. I also host Turvakäräjät-podcast, run Helsinki security meetup group HelSec and teach forensics at The National Defence Training Association of Finland.</description></item></channel></rss>