<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tools on DFIR</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/categories/tools/</link><description>Recent content in tools on DFIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>It's all about forensics</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.dfir.fi/categories/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[0x06] Cyber Security Essentials CTF</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x06-cyber-security-essentials-ctf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x06-cyber-security-essentials-ctf/</guid><description>Cyber Security Essentials is a course series I was organizing in HelSec with Future Female. CSE had 6 lectures and the CTF was organized at the end of the course. The course was aimed for female who are interested working in technical side of the Cyber Security OR just started in the field. This CTF was made 99% by me alone and was purposed to be entry level. More information about the course series can be found from here.</description></item><item><title>[0x05] Phishing MFA accounts</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x05-phishing-mfa-accounts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/07/0x05-phishing-mfa-accounts/</guid><description>MFA is usually considered secure. It however can be bypassed by phishing. I made this phishing demo using drk1wi&amp;rsquo;s tool Modlishka. The tool default templates are little bit outdated so here&amp;rsquo;s also instructions how to make it work against G-Suite accounts. This is not a new thing, I just wanted to check if it still works. =)
The full configuration is on Github.
Demo {% include vimeoPlayer.html id=page.vimeoId %}</description></item><item><title>[0x04] Installing RegRipper on Linux</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/02/0x04-installing-regripper-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2020/02/0x04-installing-regripper-on-linux/</guid><description>RegRipper is a tool made by H. Carvey (keydet89) for Windows registry analysis. The tool is perl script that is made to run on Windows. The tool can be installed on Linux distros but I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet found good instructions how to do it to share so I decided to make my own. I use the tool on the forensic courses I teach. Kudos to keydet89 for making this awesome tool.</description></item><item><title>[0x03] Disobey 2020 puzzle writeup</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</guid><description>Disobey is a Finnish hacker/cyber security conference. They release every year a hacker challenge and 50 first who solve it, get to buy the special &amp;ldquo;hacker ticket&amp;rdquo; with a cheaper price than a regular ticket. The badge that comes with the ticket is also visually different looking than a normal ticket. At the first I have to admit, this year the challenge was harder than in previous years. This was my third time I tried to do the challenge and the third time I managed to solve it.</description></item></channel></rss>