<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general on DFIR</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on DFIR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>It's all about forensics</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 16:04:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.dfir.fi/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[0x07] Migration to Github</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/09/0x07-migration-to-github/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 16:04:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2021/09/0x07-migration-to-github/</guid><description>I’ve decided to change my blog from self-hosted jekyll site to auto deployed Github hugo page.
Because of this, my blog’s RSS feed will also change. You can find the new RSS link from footer.
I will likely release more but less structured content on this blog in the future.
blog.dfir.fi CNAME will soon point to https://who1s.github.io</description></item><item><title>[0x03] Disobey 2020 puzzle writeup</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/12/0x03-disobey-2020-puzzle-writeup/</guid><description>Disobey is a Finnish hacker/cyber security conference. They release every year a hacker challenge and 50 first who solve it, get to buy the special &amp;ldquo;hacker ticket&amp;rdquo; with a cheaper price than a regular ticket. The badge that comes with the ticket is also visually different looking than a normal ticket. At the first I have to admit, this year the challenge was harder than in previous years. This was my third time I tried to do the challenge and the third time I managed to solve it.</description></item><item><title>[0x01] SANS 2019 &amp; BSides Orlando</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x01-sans-2019-bsides-orlando/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x01-sans-2019-bsides-orlando/</guid><description>Few weeks ago I left cold Finland and headed to Orlando to attend SANS FOR610 (Reverse-Engineering Malware). After signing up and buying flight tickets, I noticed that BSides Orlando was held just few days before the course started. I though &amp;ldquo;What the hell&amp;rdquo; and bought a ticket to that event as well. BSides is Disobey (Finnish hacking/cyber security event) like event and has talks, workshops, CTF, soldering station etc&amp;hellip;
BSides was held at Full Sail University near Orlando.</description></item><item><title>[0x00] Hello World!</title><link>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x00-hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.dfir.fi/posts/2019/04/0x00-hello-world/</guid><description>I decided to start blogging because
I suck at remembering stuff -&amp;gt; If I write it publicly down, I will most likely remember it There&amp;rsquo;s no DFIR blogs in Finland (at least I don&amp;rsquo;t know of them) There&amp;rsquo;s never too many projects, right? My bio can be found on about-page</description></item></channel></rss>